Guide to the Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Manuscripts, 1828-1960; Series II; 13.35; (34 boxes)
  - Manuscripts by Robert Louis Stevenson
    - [Notebooks]
      - [Untitled], 1872-1874 (Box 39, Folder 860)
        ["I do not fear to own me kin..."] (6332)
        ["I read, dear friend, in your dear face..."]
        "Inscription for the Tankard of a Society Now Dissolved," poem (6455)
        ["Let love go, if go she will..."] (6509)
        "Music at the Villa Marina" (6598)
        "Ne Sit Ancillae Tibi Amor Pudari" (6624)
        ["O dull cold northern sky..."] (6656)
        ["The old chimaeras, old receipts..."] (6671)
        ["Since thou has given me this good hope, O God..."] (6850)
        ["Swallows travel to and fro..."] (6952)
        [To F.J.S.] (6998)
        "To Madame Garschine" (7010)
        "To Marcus" (7011)
        "To Madame Zassetsky and Madame Garschine" (7013)
        "To Ottilie" (7024)
        "A Valentine's Song" (7082)
        ["The wind is without there and howl in the trees..."] (7170)
      - [Untitled], [1879-1880], undated (Box 39, Folder 861)
        ["As in their flight the birds of song..."] (5980)
        ["Death, to the dead forevermore..."] (6148)
        "An English Breeze"(6192)
        "God gave to me a child in part..." (6257)
        [In the States] (6447)
        ["It's forth across the roaring foam..."] (6471)
        ["Know you the river near the Grez..."] (6482)
        "Our Lady of the Snows" (6705)
        ["The piper..."] (6717)
        [Requiem] (6791)
        ["Small is the trust when love is green..."] (6869)
        [To F.J.S.] (6999)
        ["What man may learn, what man may do..."] (7136)
    - "Notes: Practical, Historical, and Amusing" (6640), [1867?]
    - ["Nothing have I for to say..."], poem (3326), [1868 September 26]
    - [Nous n'irons plus au bois] (6643, 3275), [1875], undated
    - ["Now bare to the beholder's eye..."] (6645), undated
    - ["Now the rain falls on the hearth of the firelight..."] (6648), undated
    - ["O dinnae mind the drams ye drink..."] (2753), [1883 May 20]
    - ["O lady fair & sweet..."] (6661), [1875]
    - "O le tala ia eatune o teira o le tala moni" (6662), undated (Box 39, Folder 862)
    - "O mana'o e tolu" (6663), undated (Box 39, Folder 863)
    - ["O sovereign of my Cedercrantz..."] (2866), 1892 December 28
    - ["O Stoddard! In our hours of ease..."] (6665), 1880
    - ["O they rode in the rain..."] (666), undated (Box 39, Folder 864)
    - "O Tuapi'o e toalua" (6668), undated
    - ["O what a bard I should have been..."] (2925), [1890]
    - ["Ode by Ben Johnson..."] (2726), [1882 January?]
    - ["Of such gray seeming with so red a heart..."] (3554), 1870 January 7
    - "An Old Song" (6106), [circa 1877] (Box 39, Folder 865)
    - "On Modern Creeds" (6675-6676), 1871, undated (Box 40, Folder 866)
    - "On Morality," essays (6677-6679), undated
    - ["On Richmond Hill in summertime..."] (6680), undated
    - ["On some ghostly companions at a spa..."] (6681), undated (Box 40, Folder 867)
    - ["On such a day as this day is..."] (6682), undated
    - ["On such a day as this, so crystal clear and fair..."] (6683), undated
    - "On the Choice of a Profession" (6684), undated (Box 40, Folder 868)
    - ["One after one, we perish and depart..."] (6691), undated
    - ["Onward Christian soldiers: being memorials..."] (6695), undated (Box 40, Folder 869)
    - [Orders on Harry Jay Moors] (6699), 1891-1892, undated (Box 40, Folder 870)
    - [Orders on Others] (6700), 1892, 1894 (Box 40, Folder 871)
    - "Our Lady of the Snows" (6704, 6706), undated (Box 40, Folder 872)
    - "Over the Water wi' Chairlie" (6708), undated (Box 40, Folder 873)
    - ["The pallid prisoner salutes the pretty Morocco..."] (6709), undated (Box 40, Folder 874)
    - "Parochial Work and Organisation" (6710), 1871 May 1 (Box 40, Folder 875-876)
    - ["Passed are the toils of the ocean..."] (6711), undated (Box 40, Folder 877)
    - [The Peasants' War, 1524-1526...] (6712), undated (Box 40, Folder 878)
    - ["A perfect cure; or the man of habit..."] (6713), undated
    - [Philip the Good, Duke of Burgundy, and Others], notes (6714), undated
    - [Photographs] (6715), undated (Box 40, Folder 879)
    - [Photographs Taken by Lloyd Osbourne...] (6716), undated (Box 40, Folder 880)
    - ["The piper..."] (6717), 1880
    - "The Plague-Cellar" (6719), undated (Box 40, Folder 881)
    - [Play (Untitled)] (6722), undated (Box 40, Folder 882)
    - [Poem for a Class Re-union] (6726), [1875]
    - [Poem Written Upon Mrs. Thomas Stevenson's Birthday...] (6727-6728), 1891 (Box 40, Folder 883)
    - [Poems by R.L.S...] (6729), undated (Box 40, Folder 884)
    - ["The poor inhabitant below..."] (3023), [1877]
    - ["Popo's grandchild, very good..."] (6730-6731), undated (Box 40, Folder 885)
    - "A Portrait" (6733-6734), undated (Box 40, Folder 886)
    - "Praise and Prayer" (6735), [1878] (Box 40, Folder 887)
    - ["Prayer... I ask good things that I detest..."] (6737), 1869 October
    - [Prayers Written for Family Use at Vailima] (6739-6740), undated
    - Prince Otto (6743-6744), undated (Box 40, Folder 888-889)
    - "Public Law" (6746), undated
    - Records of a Family of Engineers (6749-6782), undated (Box 41, Folder 890-894)
    - [Reflections and Remarks on Human Life] (6784), [1878?] (Box 41, Folder 895)
    - [Reformation], notes (6785), undated (Box 41, Folder 896)
    - ["Remarks for about 1/4 of an..."] (6787), 1852 December (Box 41, Folder 897)
    - "Reminiscences of Colinton Manse" (6788-6789), undated (Box 41, Folder 898-899)
    - [Requiem] (6790), 1879 August
    - [Requiem] (3049), [1880 February]
    - [Roads], receipt (6793), 1874 April (Box 42, Folder 900)
    - ["The roadside lined with ragweed, the sharp hills..."] (6794), 1880 August
    - [Robert Louis Stevenson to the Bard of Hanamati] (6795), [1888] (Box 42, Folder 901)
    - "Robin and Ben...", undated
    - ["Rose of all roses, the most rare..."] (6797), undated (Box 42, Folder 902)
    - St. Ives (6801-6820 and 8353), undated (Box 42, Folder 903-916)
    - "A Samoan Scrapbook" (6824-6825), [1889?], undated (Box 42, Folder 917-918)
    - [Samoan Story] (6826), undated (Box 42, Folder 919)
    - [Samoan Vocabulary], notes (6827), undated (Box 42, Folder 920)
    - "The Scarce Family," notes (6829), undated (Box 42, Folder 921)
    - "School for the Sons of Gentlemen" (6830), [circa 1877]
    - "The Scientific Ape" (6831), undated (Box 42, Folder 922)
    - [William Shakespeare. Plays], notes (6835), undated (Box 42, Folder 923)
    - ["She had that peaceful sort of beauty..."] (6836), undated (Box 42, Folder 924)
    - 'The Sick Child" (6842), undated (Box 42, Folder 925)
    - [Signatures] (6843), 1872-1894 (Box 42, Folder 926)
    - ["Silence et repos..."] (3280), 1882 October
    - [The Silverado Diary] (6844), undated (Box 42, Folder 927)
      Photostat of original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery
    - [Jules Simoneau. His Restaurant in Monterey] (6846), undated (Box 42, Folder 928)
    - ["Since I am sworn to live my life..."] (6848-6849), undated (Box 42, Folder 929)
    - "Since Years Ago Forevermore" (6852), undated (Box 42, Folder 930)
    - ["Sing clearlier, Muse, or evermore be still..."] (6854), undated (Box 42, Folder 931)
    - "Singular Instance of Intelligence in a Bogue" (6855), undated (Box 42, Folder 932)
    - "Sir Alan M'Lean's Effigy, on Inch Kenneth" (6856), undated
    - ["Sit doon by me, my canty freend..."] (6861), [1874]
    - "Skerryvore" (6862, 6864-6866), undated (Box 42, Folder 933-935)
    - "Sketches", undated (Box 42, Folder 936)
      "A Character" (6089)
      "Nuit Blanches" (6649)
      "Nurses" (6650)
      "The Satirist" (6828)
      "The Wreath of Immortelles" (7183-7184)
    - ["Slumber approaching we in our open house..."] (6867-6868), undated (Box 42, Folder 937)
    - ["So live, so love, so use that fragile hour..."] (6876), [1885] (Box 42, Folder 938)
    - ["So now I meet you once again..."] (6877), undated
    - ["So went he in the glory of his age..."] (6879), undated
    - "The Son" (6882-6884), undated
    - "Song of Tefari" (6886, 6888), undated (Box 42, Folder 939)
    - "A Song of the Road" (6889, 6892), undated (Box 42, Folder 940)
    - ["Song of the two chiefs..."] (6893), undated
    - "Songs", 1871-1872, undated (Box 42, Folder 941)
      ["About the sheltered garden ground..."] (5932)
      "After Reading 'Antony and Cleopatra'" (5949)
      "Apologetic Postscript of a Year Later" (5972)
      ["Away with funeral music..."] (5999)
      "Dedication" (6149)
      "Duddingstone" (6171)
      ["I dreamed of forest alleys far..."] (6340)
      ["I know not how, but as I count..."] (6351)
      ["Lo! In thine honest eyes I had..."] (6538)
      "Love's Vicissitudes" (6550)
      ["My heart, when the first blackbird sings..."] (6605)
      "Prelude" (6741)
      "St. Martins Summer" (6823)
      "Spring-Song" (6911)
      ["The summer sun shone round me..."] (6942)
      "The Vanquinshed Knight" (7083)
      ["You looked so tempting in the pew..."] (7199)
    - "Songs", 1870-1872 (Box 42, Folder 942)
      ["About the sheltered garden ground..."] (5931)
      "After Reading 'Antony and Cleopatra'" (5948)
      "Duddingstone" (6170)
      ["I dreamed of forest alleys far..."] (6336-6339)
      ["I sit up here at midnight..."] (6365)
      "Love's Vicissitudes" (6549)
      ["My heart, when the first blackbird sings..."] (6604)
      "St. Martin's Summer" (6822)
      "Spring Song" (6910)
      ["You looked so tempting in the pew..."] (7198)
    - Songs of Travel and Other Verses (6894-6898), undated (Box 43, Folder 943-945)
    - "Sonnets", 1870-1872 (Box 43, Folder 946)
      ["As Daniel, bird-alone in that far land..."] (5976)
      ["As in the hostel by the bridge, I sate..."] (5978)
      ["I have a hoard of treasure in my breast..."] (6347)
      "Lines To Be Sent With the Present of a Sketch Book" (6526)
      ["Nor judge me lights, tho' light at times I seem..."] (6633)
      ["Not undelightful friend our rustic ease..."] (6638)
      ["The strong man's hand, the snow-cool head of age..."] (6938)
    - "Sonnets", [1870] (Box 43, Folder 947)
      ["I have a hoard of treasure in my breast..."] (6346)
      ["The roadside lined with rag-weed, the sharp hills..."] (6794)
      "Sir Alan M'Leans Effigy, on Inch Kenneth" (6856)
      "Lines To Be Sent With the Present of a Sketch Book" (6525)
      ["Those are very clever men..."] (6977)
      "To My Pipe" (7021)
      "To the Sea" (7043)
    - ["Soon our friends perish..."] (6899-6900), [1876], undated
    - [South Sea Language] (6902), undated (Box 43, Folder 948)
    - "The Spaewife" (6903), undated
    - "Spring" (6907), [1876?]
    - "Spring Carol" (6908), undated (Box 43, Folder 949)
    - ["Stepped like divine Diana from the woods..."] (6915), undated (Box 43, Folder 950)
    - [Stevenson Family. Genealogy] (6917-6918), undated (Box 43, Folder 951-952)
    - "Stevenson's Moral and Intelligent Guide to the Claironet" (6919), undated (Box 43, Folder 953)
    - [Stewarts of Appin and Ardsheal], notes (6920), undated (Box 43, Folder 954)
    - ["Still I love to rhyme, and still more, rhyming, to wander..."] (6922), [1882]
    - "The Stimulation of the Alps" (copy) (6924), [1881?]
    - "The Stormy Evening" (6926-6928), undated (Box 43, Folder 955)
    - "Stout Marches Lead to Certain Ends" (6930-6931), 1872, undated
    - ["Strange are the ways of men..."] (6933), [1878]
    - Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde (6934-6935), [circa 1886] (Box 43, Folder 956-957)
    - ["The strong man's hand, the snow-cool head of age..."] (6938), 1872
    - "A Summer Night" (6941), 1869 October 25 (Box 43, Folder 958)
    - "The Sunbeam Magazine" (6944-6947), 1866, undated (Box 43, Folder 959-960)
    - [Sunday..."] (6948), undated
    - "The Supposed Death of Duke de Jenkins" (6949), undated
    - [The Susquehanna and the Delaware] (3037 and 6951), 1879 August
    - "The Swing," song (6953), undated
    - ["Take me and hold me let me die..."] (6954), undated
    - ['Take me and touch me; I am red and huge..."] (6955), undated (Box 43, Folder 961)
    - [Tales of Arabia] (6956), [1882]
    - "Talofa, Togarewa!" (6958), [189-] (Box 43, Folder 962)
      Includes note from Robert Louis Stevenson to Arthur E. Claxton (7958)
    - [The Tantia people..."] (6959), undated
    - [Tempest Tossed and Sore Afflicted] (6961-6962), undated
    - ["That little form but skin and bone..."] (6963), undated (Box 44, Folder 963)
    - ["Thence peering gladly forth you should..."] (6965), undated (Box 44, Folder 964)
    - ["There are heaps of pleasant places there..."] (6966), undated (Box 44, Folder 965)
    - ["There where the land of love..."] (6968), [1876]
    - ["Think not that I am sad: I know..."] (6970), undated
    - ["This is the study where a smiling God..."] (6972), undated
    - ["Those are very clever men..."] (6977), undated
    - ["Thou strainest through the mountain fern..."] (6979), undated (Box 44, Folder 966)
    - ["Though I should rise at morning..."] (3285), [circa 1885-1886]
    - "Thoughts of a Smoker" (6982), undated (Box 44, Folder 967)
    - "Thoughts on Death" (6983), undated
    - ["Three robins, first and last, have torn..."] (6984), undated
    - ["Tis thus and thus that I shall sing..."] (3551), 1868 September
    - ["Tis years since he was born..."] (3222), [1890 January?]
    - 'To a Youth" (6986), undated (Box 44, Folder 968)
    - "To Adelaide" (6987-6988), [1894] (Box 44, Folder 969)
    - ["To all that love the far and blue..."] (6989), [1880] (Box 44, Folder 970)
    - [To an Island Princess] (6990), undated (Box 44, Folder 971)
    - [To Andrew Lang] (3180 and 6992), 1886
    - "To C. W. Stoddard" (6993), [1880]
    - [To Charidemus (In Charidemum) (6994), undated
    - "To Dr. Hake" (6996), 1885 May (Box 44, Folder 972)
    - [To F.J.S.] (7000), 1881 April 3 (Box 44, Folder 973)
    - ["To friends at home, the lone, the admired, the lost..."] (7001), undated
    - ["To grow old, which is the business..."] (7002), undated (Box 44, Folder 974)
    - "To H.C. Bunner" (7003), 1885 October 21 (Box 44, Folder 975)
    - ["To higher levels I arise..."] (7004), [1880 December ?]
    - "To His Love" (7005), undated (Box 44, Folder 976)
    - [To Katharine de Mattos] (7007), undated (Box 44, Folder 977)
    - [To Lupus (In Lupum)] (7008), undated
    - [To Madame Garschine] (7009-7010), 1874
    - "To Marcus" (7011), 1872 September
    - [To Maximus (In Maximum)] (7012), undated
    - "To Mesdames Zassetsky and Garchines" (7013-7014), 1874 February
    - "To Miss Cornish" (7016), undated (Box 44, Folder 978)
    - "To Mrs. MacMorland" (7017), [circa 1880-1881] (Box 44, Folder 979)
    - ["To Mr. Charles Baxter, writer..."] (7018), undated
    - "To Mother MaryAnne" (3189 and 7019), 1889, undated
    - "To My Old Familiars" (2831 and 7020), 1890 February
    - "To My Pipe (7021), undated
    - [To My Wife], fragment (7022), undated (Box 44, Folder 980)
    - [To Nepos (Ad Nepotem)] (7023), undated
    - [To Priapus] (7025), undated
    - [To Quintilian (Ad Quintilianum)] (7027), undated
    - "To Rosabelle" (7028), undated
    - "To S.C." (7030), 1889 October (Box 44, Folder 981)
    - [To Sydney] (7031), undated (Box 44, Folder 982)
    - [To Teuila] (7034), undated (Box 44, Folder 983)
    - [To Teulia] (7035-7036), 1894, undated (Box 44, Folder 984)
    - "To the Commissioners of Northern Lights" (7038), 1871 (Box 44, Folder 985)
    - "To the Editor" (7039), undated (Box 44, Folder 986)
    - "To the Elect Lady Belinda Morocco" (7040), undated (Box 44, Folder 987)
    - "To the Sea" (7043), undated
    - "To the Stormy Petrol", 1894 March 10 (Box 44, Folder 988)
    - [To Theobald Boehm...] (7048), undated
    - [To Time] (7049), undated
    - [To Virgil and Dora Williams] (7050), undated (Box 44, Folder 989)
    - ["To what shall I compare her..."] (7051), undated (Box 44, Folder 990)
    - [Topical Song] (7054), undated (Box 44, Folder 991)
    - Travels With a Donkey (8363-8364), undated
    - Treasure Island (7062), [1885?] (Box 44, Folder 992)
    - "Tropic Rain" (7066), undated (Box 44, Folder 993)
    - ["Troubles of Paris..."] (7067), undated (Box 44, Folder 994)
    - "Trying Left Hand" (7068), undated (Box 44, Folder 995)
    - [Tutuila] (7069), 1891 (Box 44, Folder 996-997)
    - ["A una in a lion's den..."] (7070), undated (Box 44, Folder 998)
    - "Unconfirmed Rumours" (7071), undated
    - ["The unfathomable ocean runs..."] (7072), undated
    - ["Unquiet feet..."] (7073), undated (Box 44, Folder 999)
    - ["Upon a particular Monday morning in November..."] (7075), [1865?] (Box 44, Folder 1000)
    - "The Vagabond" (7076-7077), undated (Box 44, Folder 1001)
    - [Vailima], agreement (7080), [1891?] (Box 44, Folder 1002)
    - [Valentine Written For Teuila...] (7081), [circa 1893-1984] (Box 44, Folder 1003)
    - "Verses", undated (Box 44, Folder 1004)
      "Early in the Spring" (6176)
      "An End of Travel" (6190)
      "Evensong" (6202)
      ["Farewell, fair day and fading light..."] (6214)
      ["He hears with gladdened heart..."] (6278)
      ["I whom apollo sometimes visited..."] (6375)
      ["I will make you brooches..."] (6378)
      ["In dreams, unhappy, I behold you stand..."] (6408)
      "The Last Sight" (6493)
      ["Plain as the glistening planets shine..."] (6721)
      ["She rested by the broken brook..."] (6838)
      "To My Old Familiars" (7020)
      "Tropic Rain" (7065)
      "Wandering Willie" (7090)
      "The Woodman" (7181)
    - [Verses, Accompanying a Present] (7084-7085), undated (Box 44, Folder 1005)
    - "Wandering Willie" (2822 and 7088-7090), 1888, undated
    - [War Game] (7091 and 7094), undated (Box 45, Folder 1006)
    - ["Was Butler right?] (7096), undated (Box 45, Folder 1007)
    - "We Have Loved of Yore" (7098 and 7100), undated (Box 45, Folder 1008-1009)
    - ["We knew you better, dear, than you believed..."] (7102-7103), undated
    - ["We, uncommmiserate pass into the night..."] (7104), undated
    - "The Weak and the Strong" (7105), undated (Box 45, Folder 1010)
    - Weir of Hermiston (7108-7112, 7114-7124), undated (Box 45, Folder 1011-1024)
      Includes photostats of orignals at the Pierpont Morgan Library
    - [Arthur Wellesley...] (7128-7131), [circa 1884-1885] (Box 45, Folder 1025-1028)
    - ["Whan first upon the alto flute..."] (2771), [1884 April 28]
    - ["What a terrible thing is the green eyed lobster..."] (7132), undated (Box 45, Folder 1029)
    - ["What do you here to go as I was wont..."] (7133), undated
    - ["What should I do, love, if you were true, love..."] (7137), undated
    - ["When aince Aprile has fairly come..."] (7138-7139), undated (Box 45, Folder 1030)
    - ["When I was young and drouthy..."] (2754), [1883]
    - "When the Devil Was Well" (7143), [1874-1875] (Box 45, Folder 1031)
    - ["When the watch is over..."] (7147), undated
    - ["Where is my wife?"] (3285), [circa 1885-1886]
    - ["Where is now the père Martini?"] (3093), [1886]
    - ["Wherefore, O King, from Troja have we fared?"] (7152), undated
    - ["Whether in virtues, songs or tales..."] (8368), undated (Box 45, Folder 1032)
    - ["The white moon shines on roof and street..."] (7155), undated
    - "The White Nigger" (7156), undated
    - ["Why I am so penniless..."] (3073), [1883 May]
    - [Will] (7161-7165), 1885-1893 (Box 45, Folder 1033-1037)
    - ["Will had a cross bow, puss a sword..."] (7166), undated
    - [The Wind Blew Shrill and Smart] (7167-7168), undated
    - ["The wind is cold, the rain is here..."] (7169), 1881 (Box 45, Folder 1038)
    - "Windy Nights" (7172), undated
    - ["With thoughts reverential and silly..."] (3285), [circa 1885-1886]
    - [Women], notes (7177), undated
    - "The Woodman" (7179-7181), undated
    - The Wrecker (7185), undated (Box 45, Folder 1039)
    - The Wrong Box (7186-7188), undated (Box 45, Folder 1040-1041)
    - The Wrong Box (7189), undated (Box 46, Folder 1042)
    - ["Ye seek your allegiance..."] (7101), undated (Box 46, Folder 1043)
    - The Young Chevalier, fragment (7202), undated
    - "Young Rob Roy" (7204), undated
    - ["Your friend, the bold unfearing chap..."] (3062), [1881 June]
    - ["Your ideas upon Tol'rance..."] (7206), undated
    - "Youth & Love" (7207-7208), undated (Box 46, Folder 1044)
  - Manuscripts by Others
    Manuscripts by Others is arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Authors Club
      - [Minute on the Death of R.L.S.] (7209), 1894 December 3 (Box 47, Folder 1045)
    - Baildon, H. Bellyse (Henry Bellyse)
      - "The Riven Rock" (7210)
    - Balfour, James
      - "Extract from James Balfour's Accounts" (7211), undated (Box 47, Folder 1046)
    - Balfour, Michael
      - "Catalogue of Stevenson Papers" (7212), undated (Box 47, Folder 1047)
    - [Bank of Australasia, Sydney Branch]
      - Bank book (7213), 1893 (Box 47, Folder 1048)
    - Baxter, Charles
      - Agreements (7215-7217), 1894-1898 (Box 47, Folder 1049-1051)
      - Conveyance (7218), 1895 February (Box 47, Folder 1052)
      - Deed of Assumption and Conveyance (7219), 1898 August (Box 47, Folder 1053)
    - Boodle, Adelaide A.
      - [Poems] (7220), undated (Box 47, Folder 1054)
      - R.L.S. and his sine qua non (7221), undated (Box 47, Folder 1055)
    - Boyce, Neith
      - "The Sire de Malétroit's Door" (7234)
    - Burke, Thomas
      - "Concerning Robert Stevenson, Illegitimate Son of R.L.S." (8370), [1940 June] (Box 47, Folder 1056)
    - Campbell, Mungo
      - "Copy Letter from Mungo Campbell..." (7222), undated (Box 47, Folder 1057)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons
      - [Bills], 1893-1903 (Box 47, Folder 1058)
      - Royalty reports, 1893-1906 (Box 47, Folder 1059)
    - Church of Scotland. Presbytery of Edinburgh
      - [Extract From Records] (7223), 1869 May 13 (Box 47, Folder 1060)
    - Colvin, Sidney
      - "Théophile Gautier," essay (7224), 1873-1935, undated (Box 47, Folder 1061-1065)
      - "Théophile Gautier," essay (7224), 1873-1935, undated (Box 48, Folder 1066-1067)
      - "Life of Robert Louis Stevenson" (7225), [circa 1899] (Box 49, Folder 1068)
    - Commissioners of Northern Lighthouses
      - [Alan Stevenson. Minute on his Death] (7226), 1866 January 3 (Box 49, Folder 1069)
    - Dobell, Horace
      - [Silent & Grand on Skerrivore] (3124)
    - Dobson, Austin
      - ["R.L.S. in memoriam..."] (7228)
    - Duleau, A.
      - "Extract from Notice sur A. Fresnel..." (7229), 1828 July (Box 49, Folder 1070)
    - Field, Isobel
      - [Account Book] (7369), 1894-1897 (Box 49, Folder 1071)
      - [Contract] (7370), 1889 May 25
      - "Grouse in the Gun-Room" (7371), 1892-1895 (Box 49, Folder 1072-1073)
      - [Mrs. R.L.S.'s Part in the Writing of Dr. Jekyll...] (7372), 1944 April 12 (Box 49, Folder 1074)
      - "Teuila's Trip with Ned to Samoa" (8391), [circa 1915] (Box 49, Folder 1075)
    - Goring, Henry
      - [Letter] (7230), undated (Box 49, Folder 1076)
    - Grossmith, George
      - "The Real Case of Hide and Seekyll" (7231), [circa 1888] (Box 50, Folder 1077)
    - Hake, Thomas Gordon
      - "To R.L.S." (7233)
    - Hardy, Thomas
      - "Robert Louis Stevenson" (7235), undated (Box 50, Folder 1078)
    - Hellman, George S. (George Sidney)
      - "The Castaways of Soledad," prefaces (7236-7237), undated (Box 50, Folder 1079-1080)
      - "Comments on the Report of Mr. C. Kerton..." (7238), undated (Box 50, Folder 1081)
      - "Controversy Concerning Stevenson" (7239), undated (Box 50, Folder 1082)
      - "Conversation With Gelett Burgess" (7240), 1924 November 24 (Box 50, Folder 1083)
    - Henley, William Ernest
      - [Apparition] (7242), 1875-1876 (Box 50, Folder 1084)